<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>org.mixxx.Mixxx</id>
  <metadata_license>CC-BY-SA-4.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-2.0</project_license>
  <name>Mixxx</name>
  <summary>Perform live DJ mixes</summary>
  <developer_name>The Mixxx Development Team</developer_name>
  <description>
    <p>
      Mixxx is a highly customizable, cross-platform DJ application that
      integrates all the tools DJs need to perform creative live mixes.
    </p>
    <ul>
      <li>Blend songs together using automatic BPM matching and remix on the fly
      with samples, loops and hot cues.</li>
      <li>Never miss a beat with the scratchable waveform displays, volume
      normalization and accurate tempo and key detection.</li>
      <li>Spice up your mixes using high quality effects and flexible processing
      chains.</li>
      <li>Keep your music library perfectly organized with crates and
      playlists.</li>
      <li>Take a break by enabling Auto DJ with automatic crossfading.</li>
    </ul>
    <p>
      Mixxx works with many popular DJ controllers and supports vinyl emulation
      with Serato, Traktor, and Mixvibes timecodes. Whether you're an
      experienced turntablist or just getting started, Mixxx has you covered.
    </p>
  </description>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">org.mixxx.Mixxx.desktop</launchable>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/mixxxdj/mixxx/issues</url>
  <url type="contact">https://mixxx.zulipchat.com</url>
  <url type="contribute">https://github.com/mixxxdj/mixxx/blob/main/CONTRIBUTING.md</url>
  <url type="donation">https://opencollective.com/mixxx</url>
  <url type="help">https://mixxx.org/support</url>
  <url type="homepage">https://mixxx.org</url>
  <url type="translate">https://explore.transifex.com/mixxx-dj-software</url>
  <url type="vcs-browser">https://github.com/mixxxdj/mixxx</url>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://mixxx.org/theme/images/2.4/screenshots/Latenight_2decks_basic.png</image>
      <caption>Mixxx with LateNight PaleMoon skin and two decks</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://mixxx.org/theme/images/2.4/screenshots/Deere_2decks_basic.png</image>
      <caption>Mixxx with Deere skin and two decks</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://mixxx.org/theme/images/2.4/screenshots/Tango_2decks_basic.png</image>
      <caption>Mixxx with Tango skin and two decks</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://mixxx.org/theme/images/2.4/screenshots/Shade_basic.png</image>
      <caption>Mixxx with Shade skin</caption>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <releases>
    <release version="2.4.1" date="2024-05-08">
    <url type="details">https://github.com/mixxxdj/mixxx/blob/2.4.1/CHANGELOG.md</url>
      <description>
        <p>
          Mixxx 2.4.1 is a minor release with numerous bugfixes and small
          improvements. The release highlights include:
        </p>
        <ul>
          <li>Improved mappings for various controllers from Behringer, Denon,
          Hercules, Nintendo, Pioneer and Native Instruments</li>
          <li>Several UI improvements, including animated latching of sync
          button, enhanced drag &amp; drop support and more polished FX chain
          controls</li>
          <li>Added track count and duration for history playlists</li>
          <li>Improved removable drive support on Linux systems</li>
          <li>Fixes for library migration between Linux / macOS and Windows</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.4.0" date="2024-02-16">
    <url type="details">https://github.com/mixxxdj/mixxx/blob/2.4/CHANGELOG.md</url>
      <description>
        <p>
          Mixxx 2.4.0 is a major release with many new features and important
          changes under the hood. It includes the following highlights:
        </p>
        <ul>
          <li>Support for exporting crates, playlists and the library to
          Engine DJ OS devices.</li>
          <li>Added support for saved loops, which can be assigned to any hot
          cue slot.</li>
          <li>Introducing effect chains, a set of effects which can be saved and
          reloaded with all their parameters and individual meta knob
          mappings.</li>
          <li>Several new features and actions in the track menu.</li>
          <li>Support for selecting the sync leader by clicking the new crown
          symbol button next to the sync button.</li>
          <li>Added support for three different key shift algorithms.</li>
          <li>The waveform display has been rewritten, solving some longstanding
          performance issues, especially on macOS.</li>
          <li>Native support for macOS ARM systems ("Apple Silicon").</li>
          <li>Modernized JavaScript ES7 based controller mapping system and HID
          backend rework.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>